Register of the Monique Garnier-Lançon Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- European Institute for Security Matters (EIS) File, 1982-1995 (Box 9-21)
  - Correspondence
    - Delors, Jacques, 1987 (Folder 10: 27)
    - Dumas, Roland, 1988 (Folder 10: 28)
    - Eekelen, W. F. van, 1988 (Folder 10: 29)
    - Esquivie, Jean-Louis, 1984 (Folder 10: 30)
    - Giraud, André, 1988 (Folder 10: 31)
    - Goerens, Charles, 1987 (Folder 10: 32)
    - Goldsmith-Dansaert, Maryse, 1981-1988 (Folder 10: 33)
    - Goldsmitt, Jimmy, 1984-1985 (Folder 10: 34)
    - Guidi, Marcello, 1987-1989 (Folder 10: 35)
    - Haffner, Patrice, 1988 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Jaer, J. B. de, 1988 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Janssen van Raay, M. L., 1988 (Folder 11: 3)
    - King-Harman, A. L., 1986-1988 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Koch-de Graaf, Lisette, 1987-1988 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Kwint, J. A. W. F., 1988 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Labbez, Louis, 1988 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Mattingly, Mack F., 1988 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Morling, Ian, 1988 (Folder 11: 9)
    - Otten, Franz, 1988 (Folder 11: 10)
    - Pereira, Antonio Carlos, 1988 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Picq, Jean, 1988 (Folder 11: 12)
    - Plumb, Lord, 1987 (Folder 11: 13)
    - Powell, Charles, 1985 (Folder 11: 14)
    - Quinlan, Michael, 1988 (Folder 11: 15)
    - Rackwitz-van der Wielen, Hannecke, 1987-1988 (Folder 11: 16)
    - Raimond, Jean-Bernard, 1988 (Folder 11: 17)
    - Remilleux, Jean-Louis, 1984-1985 (Folder 11: 18)
    - Robert, Maurice, 1984 (Folder 11: 19)
    - Rolff, Albert A., 1988-1989 (Folder 11: 20)
    - Seynes, Jacques de, 1986 (Folder 11: 21)
    - Shea, Jamie, 1988-1991 (Folder 11: 22)
    - Sleeswyk Visser, Tjeerd, 1983-1986 (Folder 11: 23)
    - Vidrine, François, 1988 (Folder 11: 24)
    - Young, W. A., 1988 (Folder 11: 25)
    - Zurfluh, Jean-Philippe, 1989 (Folder 11: 26)
  - Dossiers
    Arranged chronologically according to Garnier-Lançon's own headings and consisting of clippings, conference papers, correspondence, lists, minutes of meetings, printed matter, reports, and speeches, all relating to the activities of the EIS
    - Administration, 1982-1987 (Folder 11: 27)
    - East-West conflicts, 1982-1985 (Folder 11: 28)
    - General information, 1982 (Folder 11: 29)
    - Publicity file, 1982 (Folder 11: 30)
    - Meeting of administrative council, Brussels, 1982 April 15 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Brussels, 1982 September 8 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Atlantic Council, 1983-1984 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Defense policy, 1983-1984 (Folder 12: 4)
    - General activities, 1983-1993 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Meetings of board of directors, Brussels, 1983 (Folder 12: 6)
    - Opposition in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union, 1983-1988 (Folder 12: 7)
    - European Conference on the West-European [sic] Defence and the Struggle for Resources and Free Enterprise, Luxembourg, 1983 May 18-20 (Folder 12: 8-9)
      Includes holograph and typescript of a conference paper delivered by Garnier-Lançon
    - European defense - current work, 1984 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Proposals, 1984 (Folder 13: 2)
    - Resistance International, 1984-1987 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Brussels, 1984 August 13 (Folder 13: 4)
    - Meeting of general assembly, Brussels, 1984 November 9 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Le rôle de la désinformation dans le monde moderne, conference sponsored by Resistance International and the EIS, Paris, 1984 December 5-6 (Folder 13: 6-8)
    - General activities, 1985-1987 (Folder 13: 9-10)
    - Membership lists, 1985-1988 (Folder 14: 2)
    - Meeting of public relations committee, Düsseldorf, 1985 January 23-24 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Brussels, 1985 February 1 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Meeting of general assembly, Rotterdam, 1985 June 21 (Folder 14: 5)
    - The Importance of the Strategic Defense Initiative for Western Europe, conference sponsored by High Frontier and the EIS, Rotterdam, 1985 June 21-22 (Folder 14: 6-7)
    - Gorbachev visit, 1985 October 2-5 (Folder 14: 8)
      Materials relating to an official visit to Paris by Mikhail Gorbachev and protests against same
    - Dinner, Paris, 1985 October 11 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Meeting of board of management, Brussels, 1985 November 6 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Visit of American officials, Paris, 1985 November 11-12 (Folder 14: 11)
    - General activities, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - Administration, 1986 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Budget, 1986 (Folder 15: 4)
    - South Africa, 1986 (Folder 15: 5)
    - Working group - industry/EIS, 1986 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Meeting of board of management, Brussels, 1986 February 28 (Folder 15: 7)
    - Meeting of supervisory board, Brussels, 1986 March 19 (Folder 15: 8)
    - Meeting of public relations committee, Eindhoven, Netherlands, 1986 April 18 (Folder 15: 9)
    - The Strategic Importance of the Export of High Technology between East and West, projected conference (cancelled), Paris, 1986 April 24-25 (Folder 15: 10)
    - L'examen des nouvelles propositions de Mikhaël Gorbatchev sur le désarmement et leur incidence sur la sécurité de l'Europe, conference sponsored by the EIS and the American Foreign Policy Council, Paris, 1986 June 16-17 (Box-folder 16: 1-9)
    - A European Defence Common Market - Myth or Reality?, conference sponsored by the EIS, European Parliamentarians and Industrialists Council, and the Defence Manufacturers Association of Great Britain, Shrivenham, England, 1986 September 18-20 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Brussels, 1986 November 25 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Meetings, 1987-1988 (Folder 18: 3-4)
    - Program, 1987 (Folder 18: 5)
    - Statutes, 1987 (Folder 18: 6)
    - Conservative Political Centre Summer School, Oxford, England, 1987 July 10-11 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Brussels, 1987 September 21 (Folder 18: 8-9)
    - Third International Roundtable Conference on East-West Relations in the 1990s: Politics and Technology, The Hague, Netherlands, 1987 October 9-10 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Meeting of board of directors, Paris, 1987 November 20 (Folder 18: 11)
    - John Beer affair, 1988-1999 (Folder 18: 12)
    - Membership dues, 1988 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Membership lists, 1988 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Pascal Lorot (application for grant from NATO), 1988 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Rackwitz-van der Wielen affair, 1988 (Folder 19: 4)
    - Sécurité civile et protection du territoire, seminar sponsored by the EIS, Paris, 1988 February 16 (Folder 19: 5-6)
    - Meeting of general assembly, Paris-Brussels, 1988 April 14-15 (Folder 19: 7)
    - Meeting of board of directors, London, 1988 May 20 (Folder 19: 8)
    - Meeting of board of directors, London, 1988 September 9 (Folder 19: 9)
    - Colloque activités spatiales militaries, Paris, 1988 October 25-26 (Folder 19: 10)
    - L'OTAN à la croisée des chemins, conference sponsored by the EIS, Brussels, 1988 October 28-29 (Folder 19: 11)
    - Latin America, 1989-1990 (Folder 19: 12)
    - Proposals, 1989-1990 (Folder 19: 13)
    - Centre d'études et de sécurité industrielle et commerciale (C.E.S.I.C.), 1989 (Folder 19: 14)
    - General activities, 1989 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Relações transatlânticas no limiar do século XXI, conference, Ponta Delgada, Azores, 1989 May 21-23 (Folder 20: 2)
      Includes holograph and typescript of speech by Garnier-Lançon, "L'Europe: une forteresse sans ramparts," 1989 May 22
    - General activities, 1990 (Folder 20: 3)
    - Projects, 1990 (Folder 20: 4)
    - Meeting of general assembly, 1990 November 9 (Folder 20: 5)
    - European meetings, 1991-1992 (Folder 20: 6)
    - Communiqué, 1991 January 17 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Russia (Nikita Chaldymov, Evgeniy Silin), 1992-1994 (Folder 20: 8)
    - Association of Euro-Atlantic Cooperation (ACEAC), 1993 (Folder 20: 9)
    - Closure, 1995 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Printed matter
    - Brochure, undated (Folder 21: 1)
    - EIS Journal
      - nos. 1-3, 1984 (Folder 21: 2)
      - nos. 3-6, 1985 (Folder 21: 3)
      - nos. 1, 3-4, 1986 (Folder 21: 4)
    - Reports
      - East Bloc Industrial Espionage, 1985 (Folder 21: 5)
      - The Future of European Security, 1985 (Folder 21: 6)
      - Freedom, Peace and Security, 1986 (Folder 21: 7)
      - Information 1/1986 (Folder 21: 8)
        Annual report
- Paris Mayor's Office File, 1980-1991 (Box 22-24)
  Dossiers consisting of clippings, correspondence, diaries, notes, photographs, and reports, relating to Garnier-Lançon's tenure as adjointe au maire de Paris, arranged chronologically according to Garnier-Lançon's headings
  - Federal Republic of Germany, 1980-1982
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982
      - A-K (Folder 22: 1)
      - L-Z (Folder 22: 2)
    - Official visits by Garnier-Lançon to the Federal Republic of Germany
      - Saare,., 1980 (Folder 22: 3)
      - Baden-Baden,., 1981 (Folder 22: 4)
      - Berlin,., 1981 (Folder 22: 5)
      - Köln,., 1981 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Rastatt,., 1981 (Folder 22: 7)
      - Bonn,., 1982 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Stuttgart,., 1982 (Folder 22: 9)
      - Titisee-Neustadt,., 1982 (Folder 22: 10)
    - Official visit by Gerhard Kunz to Paris, 1982 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Jordan, 1980-1982 (Folder 22: 12)
  - Lebanon, 1980-1982 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Folder 23: 1)
    - Diary, 1981 (Folder 23: 2)
    - Documentation, 1981 (Folder 23: 3)
      Correspondence, notes, pamphlets, reports, and other background materials
    - Press, 1981 (Folder 23: 4)
      Clippings relating to Garnier-Lançon's visit to Lebanon, 1981
  - Association culturelle franco-allemande pour la jeunesse, 1981-1982 (Folder 23: 5)
    Includes correspondence with Jacques Chirac, Roger Romani, and Jean Tiberi
  - Syria, 1981-1982 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Commission Europe, 1982 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Union démocratique européenne, 1982 (Folder 23: 8)
  - Visit to Paris by delegation from the Woman's National Democratic Club, 1984 April 9-13 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Official visit to Paris by Mikhail Gorbachev, 1985 October 2-3 (Folder 23: 10)
  - Visits to Paris by Michael, former king of Romania, 1990-1991 (Folder 23: 11)
  - Reception for Mikhail Gorbachev, Paris, 1993 June 1 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    Includes photographs of Gorbachev with Garnier-Lançon
- Mouvement Pour la Société de Développement File, 1968 (Box 24)
  Clippings, correspondence, manifesto, minutes of meetings, relating to a pro-Gaullist political movement in which Garnier-Lançon participated, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Clippings, 1968 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Manifesto drafted by Garnier-Lançon, 1968 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1968 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Publications, 1968 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Statutes, 1968 (Folder 25: 8)
- Appeal for Peace in Freedom File, 1977-1983 (Box 25)
  Brochures, bulletins, clippings, conference papers, and reports, relating to an international campaign in which Garnier-Lançon participated, arranged according to Garnier-Lançon's headings
  - Associations, 1977-1983 (Folder 25: 1)
    Brochures, bulletins, and correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Folder 25: 2-3)
  - Documentation, 1983 (Folder 25: 4-5)
    Brochures, bulletins, clippings, conference papers, and reports
- Conferences, Meetings, and Seminars File, 1980-1996 (Box 26-32)
  Conference papers, correspondence, photographs, printed matter, and speeches, relating to events in which Garnier-Lançon participated, arranged chronologically by name of conference and, for certain meetings, alphabetically by name of organization
  - General
    - Great Cities of the World Conference, Boston, 1980 September 21-27 (Folder 25: 6-8)
    - L'administration des grandes villes: colloque France-Amérique Latine, Paris, 1980 November 24 - December 4 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Europa Christiana, l'Abbaye de Royaumont, France, 1981 November 20-23 (Folder 26: 2)
    - Réunion franco-allemande, comité d'étude des relations franco/allemandes, Institut français des relations internationales, Bonn, 1982 November 29-30 (Folder 26: 3)
    - Zukunftschancen eines Industrielandes, Kongreß der Landesregierung Baden-WÜrttemberg, Stuttgart, West Germany, 1982 December 14-15 (Folder 26: 4)
      Includes photographs of Garnier-Lançon with Lothar Späth and other conference attendees
    - Neutralisme ou liberté?, Union nationale inter-universitaire, Nantes and Bordeaux, France, 1983 June 8-14 (Folder 26: 5)
    - Réunion franco-allemande, comité d'étude des relations franco/allemandes, Institut français des relations internationales, Paris, 1983 November 23-24 (Folder 26: 6)
    - Colloque international sur l'esprit de défense: une réponse des jeunes européens et américains au pacifisme, Paris, 1984 December 15-16 (Folder 26: 7)
    - How to Prevent Democracy from Perishing in Central America, conference sponsored by the American Foreign Policy Council and Resistance International, Washington, D.C., 1985 April 18 (Folder 26: 8)
    - Europäische Verteidigungsinitiative, Tutzing am Starnberger See, West Germany, 1985 September 20-21 (Folder 26: 9)
    - Workshop on Public Diplomacy, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1985 October 4-5 (Folder 26: 10)
    - Summit meeting between Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev, Geneva, Switzerland, 1985 November 19-20 (Folder 27: 1)
    - Public hearing on security policy in Europe, Political Affairs Committee, European Parliament, Brussels, 1985 December 16 (Folder 27: 2)
    - Meeting, Fundación Cánovas del Castillo, Madrid, 1986 April 4 (Folder 27: 3)
    - Tribunal Cuba, conference sponsored by Resistance International, Paris, 1986 April 11-12 (Folder 27: 4)
    - The Red Orchestra: Instruments of Soviet Policy in Africa, conference sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Washington, D.C., 1986 July 1-2 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Local Government and Defence, conference sponsored by the Academic Council for Peace and Freedom, Windsor, England, 1986 September 10-12 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Difendere l'Europa con la nonviolenza: un'utopia o una possibilità concreta?, conference sponsored by the city and province of Florence, Florence, Italy, 1987 April 28 (Folder 27: 7)
    - The Next Five Years, Conservative Political Centre Summer School, Oxford, England, 1987 July 10-12 (Folder 27: 8)
    - International Security without Nuclear Weapons, the Ditchley Foundations Conference, Oxford, England, 1988 June 3-5 (Folder 27: 9)
    - Cuba bajo analisis: realidad y perspectivas, Instituto de estudios de conflicto de la universidad del museo social argentino, Buenos Aires, 1988 June 27-30 (Folder 27: 10)
    - II Congreso internacional de estudios sovieticos, Instituto de estudios de conflicto de la universidad del museo social argentino, Buenos Aires, 1988 October 2-5 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Fall meeting, American Society for Industrial Security, Paris, 1988 November 3-4 (Folder 28: 2)
    - Internationaler Frauentag, conference, Stuttgart, West Germany, 1989 February 8 (Folder 28: 3)
    - Conference on the Democratic Alternative in the Soviet Bloc, Paris, 1989 May 9-10 (Folder 28: 4)
    - NAVO-King conference, Louvain, Belgium, 1989 October 18 (Folder 28: 5)
    - La femme musulmane et la démocratie, conference, L'Ile-de-France, 1990 March 21 (Folder 28: 6)
    - PEN 55th World Congress, Madeira, Portugal, 1990 May 6-13 (Folder 28: 7)
    - The Peaceful Road to Democracy, conference, Prague, 1990 July 4-6 (Folder 28: 8)
    - 1990 - A Decade for Freedom and Democracy, conference sponsored by the European Council for World Freedom, Brussels, 1990 July 21-26 (Folder 28: 9)
    - La Suisse - quelle place dans le monde?, rencontre internationale de Wilton Park, Basel, Switzerland, 1991 September 13-15 (Folder 28: 10)
    - La France d'aujourd'hui: réalités et problèmes, seminar organized by the Fédération des associations franco-allemandes en France et en Allemagne, Paris, 1991 October 20-27 (Folder 29: 1)
    - The Armed Forces and Military Service in a Democratic State, conference, Moscow, 1991 November 25-28 (Folder 29: 2)
    - Mieux travailler avec les allemands: des logiques culturelles aux stratégies d'affaires, seminar, Paris, 1992 April 8 (Folder 29: 3)
    - Democratization of a Society and Military Security, conference, Moscow, 1992 June 1-4 (Folder 29: 4)
      Includes holograph of remarks delivered by Garnier-Lançon
    - 37th Congress, Fédération des associations franco-allemandes en France et en Allemagne, Brest, France, 1992 June 4-8 (Folder 29: 5)
    - Pour la paix et la démocratie en ex-Yougoslavie, conference organized by Démocrates sans frontières, Paris, 1992 June 24 (Folder 29: 6)
    - Third biennial conference, European Research Group on Military and Society (ERGOMAS), Toulouse, France, 1992 July 2-5 (Folder 29: 7)
    - Europe, religions et paix, Sixième rencontre internationale pour la paix, Louvain and Brussels, Belgium, 1992 September 13-15 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - L'Asie du sud-est en devenir, conference sponsored by l'Institut français des relations internationales, Paris, 1992 October 20 (Folder 30: 2)
    - Maastricht et après?, conference sponsored by l'Institut français des relations internationales, Paris, 1992 November 3 (Folder 30: 3)
    - Greater Europe: The Idea, Reality and Prospects, conference sponsored by the International Foundation for Socio-economic and Political Studies (Gorbachev Foundation), Moscow, 1992 December 15-17 (Folder 30: 4)
    - The International System after the Collapse of the Institute for European and International Studies, Luxembourg, 1993 February 1-4 (Folder 30: 5)
    - Peacekeeping operations: une approche conceptuelle, conference sponsored by le Centre d'études de défense and l'Institut royal des relations internationales, Brussels, 1993 February 8-9 (Folder 30: 6)
    - Meeting, Association for Euro-Atlantic Cooperation, Moscow, 1993 April 6 (Folder 30: 7)
    - L'Europe introuvable, conference sponsored by l'Institut français des relations internationales, Paris, 1993 October 20 (Folder 30: 8)
    - Le développement économique, facteur de paix, conference sponsored by Mémorial de Caen and the Association Distribution Réflexion Innovation (ADRI), Caen, France, 1995 June 26 (Folder 30: 9)
    - De la dissidence à la démocratie, conference sponsored by le PEN Club français and Kontinent, Paris, 1996 March 24-25 (Folder 31: 1)
    - Le retour des communistes: un premier bilan, conference sponsored by le Club de Paris de la Dissidence à la Démocratie, Paris, 1996 June 12 (Folder 31: 2)
  - International Policy Forum meetings
    - Washington, D.C., 1985 January 11-12 (Folder 31: 3)
    - Irving, Texas, 1985 April 26-27 (Folder 31: 4)
    - Lausanne, Switzerland, 1985 July 7-10 (Folder 31: 5)
    - St. Germain-en-Laye, France, 1985 November 8-9 (Folder 31: 6-7)
    - Vienna, Austria, 1986 July 25-26 (Folder 31: 8)
    - Vienna, Austria, 1990 July 20-21 (Folder 31: 9)
  - Le Cercle (also know as Le Cercle Pinay and, subsequently, Le Cercle Violet) meetings (Box 32)
    - Wildbad Kreuth, West Germany, 1982 June 11-13 (Folder 32: 1)
    - Bonn, West Germany, 1983 June 30 - July 3 (Folder 32: 2)
    - Stellenbosch, South Africa, 1984 January 12-15 (Folder 32: 3)
    - Bonn, West Germany, 1984 July 5-7 (Folder 32: 4)
    - Washington, D.C., 1985 February 7-10 (Folder 32: 5)
    - Bonn, West Germany, 1985 June 27-30 (Folder 32: 6)
- Travel File, 1981-1994 (Box 32-35)
  Clippings, conference papers, correspondence, photographs, speeches, relating to Garnier-Lançon's travels in her official capacity as adjointe au maire de Paris or as a representative of the European Institute for Security Matters, arranged chronologically by year of visit
  - Canada, 1981 (Folder 32: 7)
  - 1982
    - United States of America (Folder 32: 8-10)
    - Middle East (Folder 33: 2-3)
      Materials relating to visits by Garnier-Lançon to Israel and Lebanon
    - South Africa (Folder 33: 4-5)
  - United States of America, 1983 (Folder 34: 1-3)
  - United States of America, 1984 (Folder 34: 4-6)
  - United States of America, 1985 (Box-folder 35: 1-3)
  - United states of America, 1986 (Folder 35: 4)
  - 1987
    - Germany (Folder 35: 5)
    - United States of America (Folder 35: 6)
  - 1990
    - Hungary (Folder 35: 7)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 35: 8)
  - United States of America, 1991 (Folder 35: 9)
  - Russia, 1994 (Folder 35: 10)
- Subject File, 1968-1991 (Box 36-44)
  Brochures, correspondence, clippings, pamphlets, photographs, serial issues, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Afghanistan - History - Soviet occupation (1979-1989), 1984-1985 (Folder 36: 1)
  - L'association européenne de Saint Vladimir, 1990 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Association internationale d'aide médicale et culturelle à l'enfance polonaise, 1988 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Blatas, Arbit, 1962-1984 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1987 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Central America - History (1979- ), 1983-1986 (Folder 36: 6-7)
    General note
    See also separate headings for individual countries
  - Centre international d'étude de la langue et des cultures d'expression française dans le monde, 1983 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Club de l'Horloge, 1982-1985 (Folder 36: 9)
  - Club 89, 1984 (Folder 36: 10)
  - Cold War, 1988 (Folder 36: 11)
  - Conference on Security and Co-operation in Europe: Final Act (1975), 1984 (Folder 36: 12)
    Materials produced by Resistance International concerning the so-called Helsinki Agreement.
  - Cuba - Politics and government (1959- ), 1983-1988 (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
  - Czechoslovakia - Politics and government (1968-1989), 1981-1983 (Folder 37: 3)
  - École supérieure de guerre, 1991 (Folder 37: 4)
  - European Integrated Information Services System (EIISS), 1988 (Folder 37: 5-6)
  - France - Politics and government (1945- ), 1983 (Folder 37: 7)
  - Fundación Cánovas del Castillo, 1986 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Germany - Foreign relations - France, 1983 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Grenada - American invasion, 1983 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Institut du futur, 1988 (Folder 38: 4)
  - Institut européen des hautes études de défense, undated (Folder 38: 5)
  - Institut français des relations internationales, 1989 (Folder 38: 6)
  - Interkerkelijk Comité Tweezijdige Ontwapening, 1985 (Folder 38: 7)
  - Iran - Politics and government (1979- ), undated (Folder 38: 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation, 1986 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon, 1984 (Folder 39: 2)
  - Latin America, 1988 (Folder 39: 3)
  - Leadership Institute, 1984 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Lebanon - Civil war (1975-1990), 1984 (Folder 39: 5-6)
  - Libya, 1985 (Folder 39: 7)
  - McFarlane, Robert, 1985 (Folder 39: 8)
  - Military policy - United States, 1988 (Folder 39: 9)
  - Mitterrand, François, 1984 (Folder 39: 10)
  - Montreal, Canada, 1981 (Folder 39: 11)
  - Namibia - History (1946-1990), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
  - National Endowment for Democracy, 1984 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Nicaragua - Politics and government (1979-1990), 1983-1988
    - 1983 (Folder 40: 4)
    - 1984 (Folder 40: 5)
    - 1985 (Folder 40: 6)
    - 1986 (Folder 40: 7)
    - 1987-1988 (Folder 40: 8)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1987-1988 (Box 41)
    - 1987 (Folder 41: 1)
    - 1988 (Folder 41: 2)
  - Oud Strijders Legioen, 1985 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), 1982-1983 (Folder 41: 4)
  - Pellecer Faena, Luis Eduardo, 1982 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Petroleum industry, 1982 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Pompidou, Georges, 1968-1969 (Folder 42: 1)
    Includes 36 photographic prints depicting Pompidou
  - PromoSpace, 1984 (Folder 42: 2)
    Materials relating to an association promoting space exploration
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1984 (Folder 42: 3)
  - Resistance International, 1983-1988 (Folder 42: 4)
  - Royal United Services Institute, 1987-1988 (Folder 42: 5)
  - South Africa - Politics and government (1978-1989), 1982-1984